i'd like to act out a movie now this
will be two two and a half hours long so
some of you are still taking this
seriously
that's not gonna work out
our kids are in the car
this is one of my favorite movies here
we go
a long time ago in the galaxy far far
away
join me luke join me on the dark side
[Music]
i'll never join you
master hello
[Music]
it's a trap
go
there is no try
[Applause]
[Music]
thank you ladies and gentlemen that was
the notebook
my wife and i we've only been in two
fights first fight we ever had was
during our engagement process you had to
register for gifts i didn't know that
i'm like let's get married again let's
get free stuff that's great
my wife want to register at a place
called bed bath and beyond have you ever
heard of that place in new york i'm a
guy though i'm like let's try this
through the bass pro shop you know what
i mean like cabela's let's go there and
uh we compromised and we went to bed
bath and beyond
awesome
pretty much in charge
[Music]
second fight we had was a couple days
ago we played this game called celebrity
crush where you share each other's
celebrity crushes and if your
relationship is going fine don't play
that game
it's a lot of attention my wife told me
her celebrity crush harrison ford
let's see she told me yeah when i was
like he's old right
well i got really jealous because i'm
like i can't compete with that right my
wife wants han solo she ended up with an
ewok
look like some of you making a
build-a-bear
i like being a dad it's my favorite uh
i'm a great dad one-on-one but when i
have them both by myself it does feel a
little overwhelming because they
outnumber me right then they go from
being my adorable children to like a
pack right they're the velociraptors
from jurassic park at that point and my
older daughter is six so she can open
doors
like the velociraptors in jurassic park
call my baby testing our fence for
weaknesses they're clever girls is what
i'm saying
right if i see one of them coming down
the hall at me it's already too late the
other one's rushing in from the side for
the kill clever girls
i'm comfortable with that
i'm kind of a nerd i don't know if you
guys could tell from that great jurassic
park joke that i just did but i also
like the movie star wars a lot so i got
my daughter and i lightsabers to play
with
for christmas one year and a while ago
we were having a little lightsaber duel
out on the front lawn a little battle of
the fates and she's like daddy i want to
go for a walk i was like all right
sweetie well go stand on the porch
because i have to run in the house and
get my keys don't get off the porch i'm
gonna be in and out in two seconds stay
on the porch so i go in grab my keys i
come out she's not on the porch she's
out in the grass swatting at bugs with
her lightsaber and i was like ooh
sweetie go inside we're not gonna go for
a walk now because you didn't listen
she's like no
i want to go for a walk
like
i told you to stay on the porch and you
didn't and there's consequences she's
like no
i'm like cool i could beat the guy
dragged a screaming child into his house
this is gonna be fun
so i walk up to my daughter
here's the thing guys she's still
holding her lightsaber
so when i get within striking distance
she takes a swing at me like a real
swing like i'ma strike you down where
you stand old man swing at me
but
i too was still holding my lightsaber
and been a nerd for a long time not
about to as a lightsaber duel to a
six-year-old right
so i smack it out of her tiny little
hand which he's lucky to have by the way
i was like
amelia
go inside i am your father
[Laughter]
such a dumb joke you guys
don't reward this baby
the weekend before that i was in
portland
and while i was there i saw a girl that
was wearing a shirt that said nerds are
cool
and i thought
are they
though they're not i don't think they
are they're not listen they're not
contrary to popular belief okay let last
time i checked those kids who are out
larping every saturday weren't using
their foam swords to fight off the
ladies okay
[Music]
that dude with a weird neck beard who
stays inside all day making youtube
tutorials for the latest minecraft
updates
he is not cool he's not
i'll tell you what's cool what's cool is
for cool kids to act nerdy yeah you just
appropriate the stuff nerds like pretend
that you did it first and make it suck
okay
it's the same thing white people have
been doing to all the stuff black people
like and it's gotta stop
it has to stop okay you already have so
many things that the nerds don't have
like friends
could you just let them have doctor who
could that be their thing please
i'm sick of it and i know they're people
ever like everybody got real quiet on
this and everyone's like
he's not talking about me i
i'm very nerdy i'm a huge star wars nerd
i'm talking about you actually
i am
oh wait
you're a fan of one of the highest
grossing and most beloved film
franchises of all time
how nerdy of you
how peculiar you are
i just want to get to know you
you're not like the other boys
[Music]
have you read the hand of thrawn trilogy
do you know how many replicas ig88 made
of himself are you single if you
answered yes to these questions maybe
you're a nerd maybe
but if you just own the trilogy congrats
you're the same level of nerdiness as
i don't know john mccain okay
doesn't make you nerdy harry potter too
liking harry potter is not nerdy okay
it's honestly actually kind of weird at
this point really
i feel strange i feel like i'm the only
person in my age group that isn't still
obsessed with harry potter
it's it's uh there's there's 30 year
olds everywhere who are like i'm a
ravenclaw no you're an adult sarah
[Applause]
you're 31 years old
your letter's not coming all right
you got to let it go sarah
i get that we love the books when we
were kids but a book that you read when
you were 12 can't still be your favorite
book today okay
you can't like if you asked me what my
favorite book was and i told you the
hatchet
you think i was an idiot
and you would be right
this dude hasn't read a book since fifth
grade no i haven't i have not
have not but gary paulsen speaks to me
oh he's so good he's so good
have you read brian's winter oh
i might like it more than the hatchet
actually
also i never even thought it was that
good of a book to begin with
i can't like people treat it like it's a
masterpiece and i'm just
sorry it's not
jk rowling did not write a masterpiece
she wrote star wars with sucky
lightsabers
she did it is like
it is so it is a direct ripoff of star
wars i am positive of it have you ever
looked at them side by side
oh what do we have here
it's a young male orphaned protagonist
who for his own safety has been sent to
live with his aunt and uncle until a
mysterious bearded stranger who was
actually the one to deliver him to his
aunt uncle when he was a baby comes into
his life and starts to teach him about
this ancient kind of magic granted he's
going to learn a lot more about this
magic from an older wiser wizard who's
high most of the time
regardless his uncle is totally against
this magic stuff he won't even tell him
what really happened to his parents but
against his uncle's wishes he leaves
home for the very first time makes some
new friends meets a pretty impetuous
young girl and though there will be an
odd sexual tension between the two of
them throughout he will only ever love
her like a sister while she struggles
with the feelings that she has for his
best friend the scruffy comic relief
and then he learns of the existence of
this super villain who killed his
parents with his sorcerer's ways before
he started calling himself lord
something or the other but quite
fortunately it turns out that our hero
is naturally good at flying and locating
incredibly small targets
two centimeters that's not impossible i
used to bullseye snitches on my firebolt
back home they're not much bigger than
two centimeters
don't touch the goblet cedric it's a
trap
i'm having a weird week the other day i
noticed
if you watch all the star wars movies
back to back
in order and really pay close attention
you're a freaking loser
[Applause]
yeah um
some of these are going to be they're
going to be jokes that's not one of them
my wife and i we're doing our best
it's hard with kids to get
wife time you know our idea of going out
and
having a night out is basically waiting
till the kids fall asleep and watching
netflix
here's how it works at our house one of
us picks out the movie
and the other one hates their life for
90 minutes
and then we switch the next week
so my wife picked out this movie one
week it's called uh it's her turn to
pick the movie she picks this movie it's
called the notes on the scandal it's
about a high school teacher that has an
affair with one of her students
my wife is a high school teacher
so right away i
hate this movie
halfway through the movie she turns to
me big smile on her face and she goes
babe
totally hypothetically
[Laughter]
what would you do
if i told you
i had an affair with a student
what kind of a game is this
it's not a fun game
i said
i don't know babe why don't you try not
to
and then she got mad at me
for how i she's like are you kidding me
you think that's something i could do
you think i'm capable of do you think i
would actually i'm just like how am i in
trouble here
what did i do
so the next week we're watching my movie
i got to pick out the movie right so
halfway through my movie i look at my
wife and i go oh hey babe
totally hypothetically
what would you do
if i told you
i was a storm trooper
it doesn't feel so good does it
she called me a i went to bed
my wife is great we've been married 16
years
well thank you
that is very nice of you but we've been
together 23 i have to say that because
she wants credit for time served
married or not been together a long time
23 years and we met a bar because 23
years ago pretty much what you had to do
we didn't have your texting and your
match.com
you had to be rejected face to face
then you had to walk away in your jedi
robe that sucked
no you do want to dance
these aren't the dorks you're looking
for
you're a dork
i was very interested in dating in my
growing up years and uh the feeling just
wasn't mutual it just wasn't
and i i thought what i need to figure
out is what do women
want
and and rather than consulting any women
i tried to figure it out on my own and
and and the conclusion i came to was
that women want a man who can do star
wars impressions
obviously and the impression that i do
well is the uh the the snow planet the
creatures they rode through the snow
like horses the uh kangaroo rats on
steroids those are the tauntauns that's
right here's my impression of the
taunton here we go
i didn't date much in high school
are there any star wars fans here star
wars fans tonight oh my god almost
everyone
fantastic i i like star wars now because
the great thing is it's a good time to
be a star wars fan because a new one
comes out every single christmas now
we're in a good thing when i was a kid
you had to wait six seven years and then
you couldn't see them on video even for
like 20 years like it was crazy now you
get them all the time it's fantastic and
uh so rogue one just came out this
christmas this past christmas but a year
before that the movie of the force
awakens came out how many people
remember the force awakens remember that
that was pretty good
so that was the first installment right
the continuation after return of the
jedi so a long time we had to wait for
that right so when i went to see it i'm
going to tell you a story is there
anyone here who hasn't seen the force
awakens but wants
to you okay you've had a year and a half
i don't know what you're waiting for
they're out we used to not do it
they went without you okay but they're
still it's on video twice okay
it's on video you get it
all right well there's a spoiler alert
in this story so if you don't want to
hear it plug your ears but yeah here we
go so you've had enough time i don't
feel sorry for it
i mean i do that you got left at that
part i feel a lot but there's plenty of
time show it towards update yeah so
okay so my wife and i go see it the
night it opens and the great thing you
guys know this because we kind of live
west of the mississippi once it's
midnight on the east coast we get to see
it late thursday night right that's one
of the cool things they don't get to do
that on the east coast so my wife and i
go see it thursday night everyone else
got to wait till friday and we come home
afterwards and uh she's texting her with
her friends and i love the four swords
so good she's texting with her friend
and she goes oh hey
her friend's husband is going the next
day they bought 10 tickets for a group
of them to go and someone doesn't isn't
going to go so they have an extra ticket
she goes hey do you want to go with them
and i was like no you know what i liked
it it was awesome i really it's a great
movie but i just saw it i don't want to
see it twice within 24 hours it's a
little too much right and uh so i go no
no go find someone to to give it to tell
him to give it away and she goes she
goes no
you should really go that would be fun
and then this is when i realized she
doesn't care if i have fun she wants to
hang out with her best friend's husband
so that we bond and then we can do
double date stuff down the road that's
really what she wants she's trying to
plant that seeds right so i tried out
smarter i was like hey you know what we
just spent 30 bucks on it tonight i
don't want to spend another 15 on it
tomorrow it's christmas time i don't
that seems like a waste of money and she
she goes no no she outsmarted me she
goes they have an extra ticket they're
just giving it to you you don't have to
pay for it i was like darn she got me
okay so she goes you should go so i was
like you know what someone's going to
want to go tell them to try and give it
away if they can't i will go so that's
how it's left okay if they can't find
someone to give it to now as i finish
the rest of the story you all seem like
very nice people hopefully you realize
i'm a nice person as well but every nice
person stops being nice at some point
right everyone has a breaking point so
as i finish this story i want you guys
to think at what point
you would have stopped being a nice
person okay
the next morning that guy calls me at
7am
some people don't already some people
already out being nice just because the
early phone call all right
i'm a comedian i sleep till noon so that
was like calling me four in the morning
i'm like what's going on he's like hey
you coming today buddy we got an extra
ticket i was like hey i got a show i'm
not sure i'm gonna be back by five he
goes he'll be back come on i was like
try and give it away but if i don't if
you don't i'll come so okay so that's
right he calls me five more times
throughout the day
right okay some people lose it
five more times finally it's four
o'clock he's like he's like he calls me
up he's like hey steve we didn't give it
away we'll see you at the theater i was
like all right so i go there i get there
it's about 10 minutes of show time i
walk in and there's him and the eight
people that are with him it's kind of
like the front row here right and uh he
introduces me to these eight people
they're the nicest people you could ever
want to meet so nice right he's like
this is bob and bob's like hey great to
meet you this is wendy oh hey i've heard
about you everyone's nice except the
very last person
he introduces me to that guy is not nice
everyone else is nice to meet you blah
blah blah and then the last person
introducing me he goes and this is
thurman
okay the guy's name is thurman okay
that's weird right away right thurman
okay this is a 40 year old man named
thurman and again if you don't think
that's weird imagine 39 years ago there
was someone looked at a baby and went
thurman no one would ever do that
no one would ever ruin a baby's life
like that and say yeah that looks like a
thurman right so let me tell you about
thurman thurman's about 40 years old uh
he's half dressed like boba fett do you
know boba fett
boba fett the bounty hunter from the
early ones so just half dress he didn't
fully commit i would have loved it if he
fully committed but only the top half
was boba fett he had the armor he had a
gun he had like a booster rock in his
back he had a helmet jack back a little
bit on his on his thing then he had
cargo shorts black socks and crocs
so he looked like if boba fett had
retired
and let himself go a little he was a
little overweight which i'm not i'm not
judging i'm a little overweight myself
but he looked like he he was not you
know what i mean he was boba fett more
than
okay he let himself go a little so
everyone else nice i don't care but but
he says to me thurman he goes everyone
says nice to meet him he goes and this
is thurman thurman looks at me and just
says
15 bucks
i go uh what he goes 15 bucks
so i look at my buddy i was like what's
he talking about he goes oh he's the one
who got all the tickets you owe him 15
bucks
like what i wasn't you're supposed to be
here
so i'm like all right i didn't lose it
at that point i reach in my pocket i'm
like my wife's involved i want to make
her look bad i reach in my pocket i have
four dollars that's all i have is four
singles i'm thinking the nice people
someone might be like don't worry about
it get us later next time we see after
the show it's gonna start now right and
so no one says anything they all just
stare at me so i'm like uh okay uh so i
look at i look at thurman i was like hey
i got my credit card how about i'll buy
some pop candy and soda that's probably
going to be more than 15 bucks i was
like how about that thurman looks at me
and goes i don't eat that crap
okay he eats that crap i eat that crap
i know other people that eat that crap
he eats it you know what i'm saying you
don't get that body from eating salads
he's not
you understand he's not boba fett is
what i'm saying
he's just being a jerk with me for some
reason right so i'm like hey i don't
know what to do see he comes with an
idea he goes he goes
there's an atm across the street
this guy hasn't seen the movie he's half
dressed like boba fett he's so excited
about the movie but he wants his if he's
15 bucks he's like there's an atm across
the street so i was like all right so i
go outside how many people would have
driven home at that point
okay yeah that's what i wish i would
have thought of that i didn't i'm still
for some reason trying to keep my head
right i go across the street i go to the
atm the atm gives me a 20 bill
okay from what i've told you about
thurman do you think he's going to have
change
no he's not going to change so i run in
the bank really quick i go to the teller
hey can you break this she goes do you
have an account here
i go no i don't have a count here she
goes we can only break it if you have an
account here i was like look you got to
help me out my wife set me up for this
double date with this guy and now this
guy thurman dressed like bobo fat just
give me a hard time she's like thurman
who names her kid thurman i was like
exactly
so she got it so she breaks it up she
gives me four fives i walk back across
the street thurman is outside the
theater waiting for me he's not even in
the lobby anywhere the movie's about to
start he's he's waiting he's like a drug
dealer ready to collect his money or
something he's gonna break my legs if i
don't have it he goes uh he goes you
have the money he saw me come for the
bank he knows i have the money right so
this is when i lost it i could not
handle it anymore at this point right he
goes uh do you have my money i go yes
here's your 15
han solo dies
did i go too far
i don't know if you've ever seen a grown
man half dressed like boba fett
crying in the fetal position outside of
an amc theater
but i personally really really enjoyed
it